Back in June at AI DevCon in London, we got four completely different answers
to what sounds like a simple question where should the agent actually run?
Let's first hear from Oleg Šelajev at Docker, who built a sandbox on containers,
was told by enterprise security teams that containers are not a boundary
they trust and went and rebuilt it on micro VMs.
All right. Hi,
my name is Oleg.
I work at Docker.
I'm a member of the DevRel team, doing all things
AI at Docker, we thought about this,
and when we were building sandboxes, we built one version with containers.
We went out, we talked to a bunch of security teams
at enterprises, and all security teams said that no, containers
are not the isolation boundary that we can trust.
So being great engineers, what did we do?
We rewrote that using micro VMs.
So containers for micro VMs might not sound like
such a big difference, but if you're sharing a kernel,
if you have a number of security vulnerabilities for exploiting
from outside of the container, that is not something that,
well, a security team can sign off because it's going to be,
well, their jobs and their reputation when the leaks will happen.
And yeah, I'll bite.
Container escaping exploits are not frequent.
There are like a dozen over the last maybe six or seven or eight years.
But as we discussed, you only need to be breached once and then it's.
And then it's bad.
So you want the hardware sort of virtual machine isolated primitive.
And this is what Docker has built for the sandboxes, the SBX
thingy that runs in micro on your machine.
And then your agent is put there within the container.
In addition to that you can this micro can run other containers.
So if you are doing using agents for software development,
the agent within this micro can do exactly what you would do.
It can run tests.
Your tests might spin up some containers, maybe with Testcontainers libraries,
maybe
just a normal Docker Compose approach, but they can create the full environment,
run your applications, and that gives you much more control
over how your agent can develop software, because it can do
whatever you would do on your machine, just fully isolated.
So and within that sandbox, within that,
there is no access to the host file system.
You choose what you share with the thing.
You have the networking proxy.
So all the requests out of the sandbox go through that.
So you have control saying, please forbid all access to Pastebin.
So if the agent wants to steal the keys, it cannot do that this way.
And there is also a secrets injection mechanism.
So the agent inside doesn't have access to your private data
while still be able to do things on your behalf.
We also heard from Luke Marsden, CEO of Helix ML,
who takes the opposite view — from your laptop, entirely.
Put the agents on the organization's infrastructure
so the work can be handed between people in different time zones.
His line is that you should give each agent their own computer.
The first big
decision, in my opinion, is: do you want to carry on
letting every developer run whatever agent they like, or maybe
the same agent that everyone uses in the company,
but on their own specific development environment?
That's kind of like a snowflake.
Or do you want to create a pool of
agents that run on your organization's infrastructure
that many humans can interact with?
And my strong argument is that.
Going for the centralized approach
and I say centralized, it doesn't mean you have to
hand over all your data to OpenAI or run on their infrastructure or anything.
You can run it on your own infrastructure.
Still on Kubernetes or something, but there are
some significant benefits from having a centralized approach.
For example, you can have a globally distributed team
all around the world, and you can say
that when the sun sets in Tokyo and rises in London,
whoever a different human can carry on doing the work
that a certain agent was working on, especially if that agent truly
has its own computer for that specific task.
And so there's a really nice
article written by by someone.
We've been working with a company called Dev Icon,
and what they said was, to be honest, agentic coding is not new.
Going from doing it the easier way, which is the way on the left
which is unsafe and per engineer to something global per company
and safe is what they found interesting in this approach.
So that's kind of my argument.
My opinion number one is
you should
give each agent their own computer, not each human.
It's almost like you wouldn't hire
a team of software developers and ask them all to share one computer.
You should give each agent their own computer.
Lars Trieloff is a principal scientist at Adobe, and he built an agent
that runs inside the browser and drives the browser it's running in.
There's also a reveal at the end of his talk that I'll let him deliver himself.
How do we get started with this?
And the.
The idea that I came up with was an agent that is sitting in the browser.
It's actually running in the browser, which means it's not a cloud runtime
where the agent loop runs and you're just displaying in the browser,
but it's actually the actual agent loop is in the browser.
To close the browser tab, the agent loop starts,
and at the same time this agent should be able to control itself.
It should control it should
it should control the browser that it's running inside.
And this is how I came up with this notion of the self-licking ice cream cone.
And that's why you find it at SLICC,
sliccy.com
And while building it,
there are a bunch of things that I was absolutely sure.
Well it's a browser right.
It can display HTML pages.
But there are a lot of things that it suddenly cannot do right.
So cannot transcode videos.
It suddenly cannot access my local file system.
But I'm fine with these constraints.
But in reality, I found during this exploration
that there are so many things
that my browser can do that I didn't even dare to think about.
And that was one of the things that made this exploration extremely fun.
And now you're wondering what this what this slide means.
And this slide means that I haven't been showing
you a presentation for the past ten minutes.
I've been showing you SLICC.
I've been showing you the very agent that we are going to talk about.
And to close, Steve Ruiz, founder and CEO of tldraw, with the answer
nobody else gave the agents live on the canvas
as little characters you can pick up, throw, and talk to.
Then he selects three at once and they elect a leader.
We wanted to bring it onto the canvas in the same way that, like,
you know, other users are on the canvas.
So that led us to.
To fairies.
To these guys.
So each one of these is an instance of that,
that harness that lives kind of on the canvas.
And while it started with just being like a way of visualizing the
agents — number one, like, just where are they?
Which ones exist, which one is which. Right.
You can kind of configure them
and change their hat
Or, because we needed two things, like, you can change the length of their legs.
I don't know if you can see that, whatever — you can toss them around.
You can hold them.
They don't like that.
Yeah. Right on.
But you can talk to them as well.
Make a move as X and you can
you can visualize the state of the agent as well.
So whether it's thinking or reviewing or working
cool.
Make a move as
Oh, and you can ask them to do things.
And again, it's pretty much the same harness as
we looked at with the whole cat on the table thing.
But there they can exist simultaneously.
They know about where each other are.
This is worse on live coding, by the way.
Let me try this.
Maybe we can get them to work as a team.
So if I grab all three of them and I say play a full
game of tic tac toe.
Then they will operate as a unit.
One of them will be elected leader and will draft a plan.
Their wings will change colors to indicate that they're on the same team.
By the way, this is also collaborative.
You could have multiple people kind of sharing the same experience.
Coordinator comes up with a to-do list and then delegates
those tasks to different fairies, different agents.
Thanks for watching.
Be sure to join us for the next AI DevCon this November in New York City.
Visit ainativedev.io to learn more and book your ticket